A Guide to the J. Sargeant Reynolds Papers, 1965-1991
Virginia Historical Society
- High School Commencement materials. (Box 14)
  - Montevideo High School (Rockingham County), 15 June 1970.
  - Lucy Addison High School and Burrell Memorial School of Practical Nursing, Roanoke, 5 February 1971.
  - Miscellaneous high school speeches.
- J. Sargeant Reynolds's Final Illness. (Box 14 (cont.))
  Contains clippings, correspondence, press releases, and medical papers concerning the medical condition of Lieutenant Governor Julian Sargeant Reynolds.
  - Correspondence, 1970.
  - Press release, 1970.
  - Telegrams, 1970.
  - Resolution, City of Roanoke, Virginia, 8 September 1970.
  - Medical information.
  - Letters of support.
  - Thank yous to doctors.
  - Public statements.
  - Clippings.
- Death of J. Sargeant Reynolds. (Box 15)
  Includes clippings, condolences, press releases, funeral arrangements and published notices concerning the death of lieutenant governor Julian Sargeant Reynolds on 13 June 1971.
  - Condolences.
  - Funeral expenses.
  - Press releases.
  - Funeral plans.
  - Death announcements (newspaper clippings).
  - Death announcements (published announcements).
  - Resolution of Reynolds Metals.
  - Miscellaneous.
- Portrait Dedication. (Box 15 (cont.))
  Includes contracts, correspondence, and clippings concerning the portrait dedication to commemorate the late Lieutenant Governor Julian Sargeant Reynolds.
  - Correspondence.
  - Clippings.
- J. Sargeant Reynolds Community College. (Box 16)
  Contains correspondence of and about Mary Ballou Reynolds Ballentine (second wife of Julian Sergeant Reynolds) concerning J. Sargeant Reynolds Community College Richmond, Va. Also, includes materials on the grand opening celebration, dedication, first commencement and inauguration of the president of J. Sargeant Reynolds Community College in Virginia.
  - Correspondence.
  - Grace Street opening, 22 October 1973.
  - J. Sergeant Reynolds dedication, 2 November 1974.
  - 1st Annual Commencement.
  - Inauguration of President, 16 January 1973.
  - Ground breaking, 16 January 1973.
  - Clippings and publications.
- Reynolds Homestead, Critz, Va. (Box 16 (cont.))
  Includes press releases, correspondence, clippings, and speeches pertaining to the opening of the Reynold's homestead near Critz, Patrick County, Va.
  - Correspondence re: Opening ceremony.
  - Speech.
  - Press release.
  - Clippings.
  - Day of Recognition, 28 May 1972.
  - Miscellaneous.
- Biographical Information on J. Sargeant Reynolds. (Box 17)
  Includes biographies and chronologies pertaining to the life of Julian Sargeant Reynolds.
  - Printed Biography.
  - Drafts of Biography.
- Materials relating to Virginia (Weir) Reynolds and children. (Box 17 (cont.))
  Includes clippings and correspondence of Julian Sargeant Reynolds relating to his first wife, Virginia Weir, and their children.
  - Correspondence with Reynolds children at camp.
  - Marriage announcement.
  - "Meet the Wife," 7 January 1966.
- Materials relating to Mary (Ballou) Reyolds Ballentine. (Box 17 (cont.))
  Includes correspondence and clippings of and about Mary (Ballou) Reynolds Ballentine (second wife and widow of Julian Sargeant Reynolds).
  - Weeks, J.
  - Tillotson, Rex.
  - Witt, W. Luke.
  - Benson, Lloyd.
  - Kret, Connie.
  - 6.McCutcheon, Andrew.
  - Shires, Carl.
  - Reynolds, R. S.
  - Miscellaneous letters.
  - Clippings.
- Personal Correspondence of J. Sargeant Reynolds and A. Linwood Holton, Jr. (Box 17 (cont.))
  Includes personal correspondence of Julian Sargeant Reynolds and Virginia Governor, A. Linwood Holton, Jr.
  - Correspondence, Personal.
  - Clippings.
  - Printed material.
- Mrs. R. S. Reynolds Materials. (Box 17 (cont.))
  Includes personal correspondence of Mrs. R.S. Reynolds (mother of Julian Sargeant Reynolds).
  - McCutchen, Andrew.
  - Fox, Paul.
- Miscellaneous Information. (Box 18)
  Includes miscellaneous information and correspondence with and about J. Sargeant Reynolds.
  - Mehringe, Judge (1991).
  - Virginia State College auditorium dedication (1976).
  - Woodberry Forest School Alumni Bulletin / Sale of Radio Station WGOE.
  - Correspondence, Chapman Associates brokerage firm.
  - Correspondence, 1964.
  - Correspondence, 1965.
  - Correspondence, 1966.
  - Correspondence, 1967.
  - Correspondence, 1968.
  - Contractual agreements, financial statements.
  - Miscellaneous.